<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Arthur Douillard</title>
    <link>/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Arthur Douillard</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD Grind</title>
      <link>/books/phd-grind/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/phd-grind/</guid>
      <description>PhD Grind (pdf url) is not strictly speaking a book, but rather a pdf memoir. It is the story of a PhD, during its six long years, in the USA in Computer Science (Model checking &amp;amp; HCI).
I found this book fantastic. As a first-year PhD, it really talked to me. I was interested to discover the PhD system in the USA, which sounds quite different from what I know in France.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ball Lightning</title>
      <link>/books/ball-lightning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/ball-lightning/</guid>
      <description>Ball Lightning is an early book of Cixin Liu, the Three-Body Problem trilogy author. While not as good as its trilogy, the book was interesting to read because of its theme: Science.
The protagonists try to understand the ball lightning (a real phenomenon). The whole book is structured around their experiments, their thoughts, and failures. The end of the book goes a bit far, and is clearly &amp;ldquo;science-fiction&amp;rdquo;, but still in a &amp;ldquo;hard&amp;rdquo;, plausible way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flowers for Algernon</title>
      <link>/books/algernon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/algernon/</guid>
      <description>This book is cataloged as sci-fi, and it actually won a Nebula and Hugo prize, so good sci-fi it should be. But if you don&amp;rsquo;t like sci-fi, give it a try anyway. Published in 1959, the book epoch doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter and except a few details it could happen right now in the 2020&amp;rsquo;s.
The narrator, Charly Gordon, is mentally disabled with a IQ in the 80 range, and we read the regular reports he write.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mr Ma and Son</title>
      <link>/books/mr-ma-and-son/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/mr-ma-and-son/</guid>
      <description>This is the story of a father and his son. Coming from Beijing, they come to London with different goals. The son hopes to learn and to held a business, the father just follow the stream.
The story itself isn&amp;rsquo;t very interesting. What I liked in this book was the description of racism and inter-generational gap.
English men are deeply racist against Chinese men, but the latter &amp;mdash;especially the old generation&amp;ndash; also hold preconceived ideas on the western culture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Kiter Runner</title>
      <link>/books/the-royal-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/the-royal-game/</guid>
      <description>First book of Afghan-American author Khaled Hosseini, the story starts in an Afghanistan I&amp;rsquo;ve never known: not particularly rich, but stable, with movies, and a relative religion liberty. The narrator, son of a rich merchant, is unsufferable but his behavior as a young man will become a burden to the man he&amp;rsquo;ll become. And this burden will have to be lifted through the adversity of the Talibans.
Characters are realistic and their story in chaos that follow the coup dethroning the king is poignant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ride of a Lifetime</title>
      <link>/books/ride-of-a-lifetime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/ride-of-a-lifetime/</guid>
      <description>https://www.gatesnotes.com/Books/The-Ride-of-a-Lifetime</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Royal Game</title>
      <link>/books/the-kite-runner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/the-kite-runner/</guid>
      <description>I have been recommended often Zweig, and I recently started to learn more seriously chess. Therefore, the first book I read written by Zweig shall be &amp;ldquo;The Royal Game&amp;rdquo;, a book about the madness induced by chess to an ordinary man.
The style is simple to follow, and the excitation created by the parties the characters engage into is contagious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Three-Body Problem trilogy</title>
      <link>/books/three-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/three-body/</guid>
      <description>Except the Sun Tzu&amp;rsquo;s Art of War, the Three-Body Problem first tome was my first Chinese book. The first book set the tone, starting in communist-era in the 70s.
When I introduce this trilogy to friends, I often say &amp;mdash;no spoilers:
 Several of world best theoretical physicists suicide. They all leave a note, saying in substance: &amp;ldquo;Physic doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist&amp;rdquo;.
 You don&amp;rsquo;t need to know more to go buy this book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Very Short Introduction: Food</title>
      <link>/books/very-short-intro-food/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/very-short-intro-food/</guid>
      <description>Very Short Introduction (VSI) is an Oxford collection about various subjects, ranging from humanities (arts, religion, politics, etc.) to very technical field (neuroscience, physics, etc.). With a small format (~100 pages), they aim to be a good introduction.
VSI: Food fulfills perfectly this mission. The book is simple enough for a neophyte in food to understand, and still manages to cover a wide breadth of topics, all centered around food. It&amp;rsquo;s far easier than its cousin VSI: Nutrition.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>